{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question_id": 2,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A box contains 20 balls, of which 12 are red and 8 are blue. If two balls are to be drawn from this box at random without replacement, what is the probability that one ball will be red and the other will be blue?",
      "options": {
        "A": "1/96",
        "B": "6/25",
        "C": "24/95",
        "D": "48/95",
        "E": "1"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 44,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A software company named Hardsoft has three divisions, each staffed by at least 10 people. The ratio of men to women is 7:5 in Finance and Administration, 3:4 in Marketing and Sales, and 8:7 in Research and Development. If there are 100 men working in Hardsoft and every Hardsoft employee works for one of the three divisions, then the difference between the maximum and minimum possible number of women working in Hardsoft is:",
      "options": {
        "A": "39",
        "B": "40",
        "C": "41",
        "D": "42",
        "E": "more than 42"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 45,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "Two guns were fired from the same place at an interval of 10 minutes and 30 seconds, but a person in a train approaching the place hears the second shot 10 minutes after the first. The speed of the train (in km/hr), supposing that sound travels at 330 m/s is:",
      "options": {
        "A": "19.8",
        "B": "58.6",
        "C": "59.4",
        "D": "111.8"
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 49,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A store purchased an article at a wholesale price of $75 and sold it at two successive discounts of 20% and 16.67% respectively, making a profit of 33.3% on the whole price of the article. The store sold another similar article at the same price, making a loss of 33.3% on the whole price. If the second article has a mark-up of 200% over its retail selling price, find by what percentage the mark-up price of the second article is more than that of the first article?",
      "options": {
        "A": "50",
        "B": "75",
        "C": "100",
        "D": "125",
        "E": "200"
      },
      "correct_answer": "E",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 53,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A customer using a certain telephone calling plan pays a fee of $25 per month, and then receives a discount of 40% on the regular charge for all calls made to country A. If calls to country A are regularly charged at $1.60 per minute for the first 3 minutes, and $0.80 per minute for each minute thereafter, what is the maximum the customer could have saved over regular prices if he was charged for 1 hour of calls made to country A in a certain month?",
      "options": {
        "A": "$8.75",
        "B": "$12",
        "C": "$13.40",
        "D": "$17.40",
        "E": "$24.40"
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 58,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A bicyclist travels 8 miles due west at a constant speed. Next, she rides x miles in a straight line in a direction somewhere between north and east, traveling at half the speed. She stops when she is due north of her starting point, at which time she is y miles from her original location. She then rides, at 1/3 of her original speed, due south for x/2 miles, at which point she ends her trip, more than x/3 miles from her starting point. If x and y are integers, how many total miles did she cycle?",
      "options": {
        "A": "15",
        "B": "24",
        "C": "32.5",
        "D": "33.5",
        "E": "40"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 59,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A lady went to the market with a few one-rupee notes and a few 20-paise coins. When she returned, she had as many one-rupee notes as she originally had 20-paise coins and vice versa. She actually came back with about one-third of what she had gone with. How much did she spend in the market?",
      "options": {
        "A": "14.40",
        "B": "14.70",
        "C": "15.50",
        "D": "17.40",
        "E": "None of these"
      },
      "correct_answer": "A",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 64,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "Pankaj started walking from point A to point B and Prakash started walking from point B to point A, both started at 6:00 AM. After walking for 2 hours, both met each other and sat down for breakfast, which took 1 hour. Then both continued their journey. Since they just had their breakfast, their speed reduced to half of their original speed. After one hour, Prakash realized that their keys got exchanged, so he started running towards Pankaj at two and a half times his present speed. If the ratio of Pankaj's and Prakash's original speed was 3:2, at what time would Prakash and Pankaj meet to exchange their keys?",
      "options": {
        "A": "12:00 PM",
        "B": "12:30 PM",
        "C": "01:00 PM",
        "D": "01:30 PM",
        "E": "11:30 AM"
      },
      "correct_answer": "B",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 65,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A bike running at 80 km/h initially is slowed down to 60 km/h as soon as the fuel indicator touches the half level mark. It keeps running at this speed till it runs out of fuel, thereby covering a total distance of 640 km in 10 hours. If the bike consumes 2 litres of fuel per hour, what is the capacity (in litres) of the fuel tank of the bike?",
      "options": {
        "A": "16",
        "B": "20",
        "C": "32",
        "D": "40",
        "E": "56"
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 66,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A chord is drawn inside a circle, such that the length of the chord is equal to the radius of the circle. Two circles are drawn, one on each side of the chord, each touching the chord at its midpoint and each tangent to the original circle. What is the ratio of the area of the bigger inscribed circle to the area of the smaller inscribed circle?",
      "options": {
        "A": "(1+√2):1",
        "B": "(2+√3):1",
        "C": "(7+4√3):1",
        "D": "(9+4√3):1",
        "E": "(97+56√3):1"
      },
      "correct_answer": "E",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 68,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A and B are two laborers who have been given the task to build a house. A can build a house in 20 days while B can build it in 30 days. But B went rogue and instead of building the house, he starts breaking it at the same rate. If A starts the work on the 1st day and they work alternately, in how many days will the house get built? (Assume once the house gets built, they will stop working)",
      "options": {
        "A": "60 days",
        "B": "115 days",
        "C": "120 days",
        "D": "140 days",
        "E": "121 1/3 days"
      },
      "correct_answer": "B",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 69,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A 3-sided rectangular pen is being built to hold 15 cows while allowing them access to a river. If each cow requires 30 square feet of grazing inside the pen and the sides of the fence will be built to integer lengths, which of the following could be the length of the fencing required to build the pen?",
      "options": {
        "A": "45",
        "B": "55",
        "C": "62",
        "D": "65",
        "E": "70"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 70,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "Two motorcyclists, Ajay and Vijay, start simultaneously from a point S on an oval track and drive around the track in the same direction, with speeds of 29 km/hr and 19 km/hr respectively. Every time Ajay overtakes Vijay (anywhere on the track), both of them decrease their respective speeds by 1 km/hr. If the length of the track is 1 km, how many times do they meet at the starting point before Vijay comes to rest?",
      "options": {
        "A": "2",
        "B": "3",
        "C": "5",
        "D": "6",
        "E": "None of these"
      },
      "correct_answer": "B",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 71,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "On January 1, 2076, Lake Loser contains x liters of water. By Dec 31 of that same year, 2/7 of the x liters have evaporated. This pattern continues such that by the end of each subsequent year the lake has lost 2/7 of the water that it contained at the beginning of that year. During which year will the water in the lake be reduced to less than 1/4 of the original x liters?",
      "options": {
        "A": "2077",
        "B": "2078",
        "C": "2079",
        "D": "2080",
        "E": "2081"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 74,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "Car B begins moving at 2 mph around a circular track with a radius of 10 miles. Ten hours later, Car A leaves from the same point in the opposite direction, traveling at 3 mph. For how many hours will Car B have been traveling when car A has passed and moved 12 miles beyond Car B?",
      "options": {
        "A": "4π–1.6",
        "B": "4π+8.4",
        "C": "4π+10.4",
        "D": "2π–1.6",
        "E": "2π–0.8"
      },
      "correct_answer": "B",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 80,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "Warren invested $5,000 for two years at a simple annual interest rate of x percent and invested $3,000 for two years at an annual interest rate of 8 percent compounded quarterly. If after 2 years both investments earned the same amount in interest, what is the approximate value of x?",
      "options": {
        "A": "1%",
        "B": "2.5%",
        "C": "5%",
        "D": "7.5%",
        "E": "10%"
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 82,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "It takes 6 days for 3 women and 2 men working together to complete a work. 3 men would do the same work 5 days sooner than 9 women. How many times does the output of a man exceed that of a woman?",
      "options": {
        "A": "3 times",
        "B": "4 times",
        "C": "5 times",
        "D": "6 times",
        "E": "7 times"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 83,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "Cities M and N are 600 miles apart. Bus A starts from city M towards N at 9 AM and bus B starts from city N towards M at the same time. Bus A travels the first one-third of the distance at a speed of 40 miles per hour, the second one-third at 50 miles per hour and the third one-third at 60 miles per hour. Bus B travels the first one-third of the total time taken at a speed of 40 miles per hour, the second one-third at 50 miles per hour and the third one-third at 60 miles per hour. At what distance will the two buses cross each other?",
      "options": {
        "A": "300 miles from M",
        "B": "280 miles from M",
        "C": "305 miles from M",
        "D": "295 miles from M",
        "E": "350 miles from M"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 89,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "A 6 cm long cigarette burns up in 15 minutes if no puff is taken. For every puff, it burns three times as fast during the duration of the puff. If the cigarette burns itself in 13 minutes, then how many puffs has the smoker taken if the average puff lasted 3 seconds?",
      "options": {
        "A": "20",
        "B": "30",
        "C": "15",
        "D": "50",
        "E": "10"
      },
      "correct_answer": "A",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 95,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Arithmetic",
      "question": "The GDP of a country is $13.8 billion, and the total production of one of its industries is $3.3 billion. If the GDP were to grow by 5% per year in the future, which of the following would be the MINIMUM required annual growth in this industry that would make it represent more than half of the GDP in ten years?",
      "options": {
        "A": "10%",
        "B": "15%",
        "C": "20%",
        "D": "25%",
        "E": "30%"
      },
      "correct_answer": "B",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    }
  ]
}